Daniel Camba Lamas

C++/Graphics Software Engineer

🔗 cambalamas.com 🖂 hello@cambalamas.com 📍 Ourense, Spain 📁 Native 🖼 B1 🚔 B

ABOUT ME

I am Daniel, a passionate Software Development Engineer with academic and professional experience in backend development as well as low-level tasks like computer graphics, memory management, multithreading apps, used to create tools focused on final user.

Achievements

- Improvement of workflows, reducing one-week tasks to around two-days tasks.
- Transform a monolithic to a RESTful API based system, saving in 75% code to maintain.

Strengths

Committed, cooperative, fast-learn, positive attitude, confident in TDD and Agile envs.

Focused on

Deep know-how of C++, clean code, automation, graphics APIs, keep learning and growing.

EXPERIENCE

R&D Engineer 06/2018 - 07/2019

Polytechnical university of Madrid - Bioengineering and Telemedicine Group

- Maintenance of legacy projects based on C++ fixing memory-leaks and minor bugs.
- Part of the team that build an environment with Unity 3D for the creation, edition and simulation of minimally invasive surgery tasks.
- Codebase reduction of 75% implementing a RESTful API for DB's C.R.U.D. with user-auth and licensing system.
- UX improvement of the evaluation process building a web-app to digest metrics generated by the training-environment and visualize on charts.
- Construction of the brand of the project from the logos to the landing page, achieving a strong visual identity adapted to the target market.

Skills: C++, Go, Unity, Html, CSS, JavaScript, Restful API, Web-Token auth system, Valgrind, TDD.

Backend Engineer 01/2017 - 04/2017

Profocus Estudio - Ecommerce Photography Studio

Automation of internal processes in the production line, from product reception to the invoicing stage. Saving time and resources.

Skills: Python, Odoo, Html, Css, Javascript, Docker, TDD.

EDUCATION

MSc in Computer Graphics 2017 - 2019

University Rey Juan Carlos - Madrid, Spain

Thesis: From scratch 3D interactive animator that load real motion-capture data and computes interpolations between different animations (e.g. walk to run, run to jump)

Skills: C++, OpenGL, Unity, GLSL, 3D-Maths, C#, Multithreading, Valgrind, GDB.

BSc in Computer Science 2012 - 2017

University of Vigo - Ourense, Spain

Thesis: Interactive mockup definition tool to prototype the behaviour of an application for a better customer's understanding of the final product.

Skills: C++, Python, PHP, Html, Css, Javascript, Qt, Django, Linux, Bash, Docker.